North Carolina Cooperative Extension, Dare County Master Gardeners Records ORG.5092
North Carolina Cooperative Extension, Dare County Master Gardeners Records
1992-2004
ORG.5092
2.000
The Master Gardeners program is part of the North Carolina State Cooperative Extension Service. The program provides educational opportunities for Master Gardeners, as well as a forum where Master Gardeners can exchange information and expertise with others. Members organize and participate in outreach projects and fundraisers. The North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners Records consist of papers from the Dare Master Gardener Volunteer Association, and includes correspondence, photographs, meeting minutes, press releases, newspaper clippings, and a handbook.
North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.
Outer Banks History Center
Box Box 1
Box Box 2
Collection Arrangement
This collection is divided into three main series: Meeting Minutes, Organizational Papers, and Photographs.
Access Restrictions
Available for research.
Historical Note
The Master Gardeners program is part of the North Carolina State Cooperative Extension Service. The program provides educational opportunities for Master Gardeners, as well as a forum where Master Gardeners can exchange information and expertise with others. Members organize and participate in outreach projects and fundraisers. The first Master Gardener class in Dare County was held in 1992.
Some of the Master Gardeners beautification projects have included the Dare County libraries, Hayman Boulvard, sea oats planting, and the Wanchese intersection. The group's primary project is the Outer Banks Arboretum and Teaching Garden. The Arboretum and Teaching Garden is meant to be an outdoor classroom that will provide horticultural education, memorial acknowledgement and enhancement properties. The goal of the garden is to test and display labeled plantings and planting practices that are suitable for a coastal environment, and to provide a garden for the pleasure of all citizents and visitors of Dare County. It features a number of theme gardens, such as the Central Garden, a Butterfly Garden and the Dune Garden. The Outer Banks Arboretum and Teaching Garden is located adjacent to the Thomas A. Baum Senior Center in Kill Devil Hills, North Carolina.
Custodial History
Formerly classified as 33MSS-92
Acquisitions Information
Donated by Susan Ruiz-Evans in 2008.
Collection Overview
The North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners Records consist of papers from the Dare Master Gardener Volunteer Association, and includes correspondence, photographs, meeting minutes, press releases, newspaper clippings, and a handbook.
Master gardeners--North Carolina--Dare County
Gardening--North Carolina--Dare County; Urban beautification--North Carolina--Dare County
- Collection Inventories, 41603; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:2.1)
- Meeting Minutes, 46835; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners
  - General Meetings, 41604; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:3.1)
  - Start Up Committee, 41605; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:3.2)
  - Executive Board, 41606; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:3.3)
- Organizational Papers, 46836; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners
  - Master Gardener's Handbook, 2004; 41607; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.1)
  - Correspondence, 41608; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.2)
  - Master Gardener Course Outline, 2004; 41609; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.3)
  - A Lesson Plan on Seeds, 41610; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.4)
  - Program Progress Report, 1995; 41611; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.6)
  - Volunteer Requirements and Opportunities, 1996; 41612; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.7)
  - Dare Day Booths, 1993-1996; 41613; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.8)
  - Terra Ceia Farms Fall Fundraiser, 1993-1994; 41614; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.9)
  - Garden Project Proposal, 2000; 41615; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.10)
  - Facility Request Forms, 41616; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.11)
  - Sodbuster Newsletter, 41617; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.12)
  - Dare County Master Gardener Association Newsletter, 41618; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.13)
  - Press Releases, 41619; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 41620; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.15)
  - Ephemera, 41621; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:4.16)
- Photographs, 46837; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners
  - Master Gardener Planning and Training Sessions, 41622; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:5.1)
  - Master Gardener Meetings, 41623; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:5.2)
  - State Conferences, 41624; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:5.3)
  - Garden Tours, 41625; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:5.4)
  - Master Gardener Classes, 41626; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:5.5)
  - Master Gardener Graduations, 1993-1994, 1998; 41627; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:5.6)
  - Coastal Gardening Festival, 41628; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:5.7)
  - Appreciation Dinners, 1996, 2002; 41629; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 1:5.8)
  - Arboretum and Teaching Garden, 41630; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.9)
  - Christmas Centerpieces, 41631; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.10)
  - Butterfly Garden, 41632; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.11)
  - ADAP Programs, 41633; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.12)
  - Wanchese Intersection Project, 1992; 41634; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.13)
  - Britthaven Planting Project, 1993; 41635; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.14)
  - Manteo and Kill Devil Hills Libraries Project, 1993; 41636; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.15)
  - Hayman Blvd. Project, 1997; 41637; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.16)
  - Sea Oats Planting Project, 1998; 41638; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.17)
  - 4-H Summer Camp Project, 2002; 41639; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.18)
  - Plant Clinics, 1992, 1997; 41640; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.19)
  - Native Plants Workshop, 1997; 41641; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.20)
  - Miscellaneous Projects and Workshops, 41642; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.21)
  - Miscellaneous Images, 41643; North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service. Dare County Master Gardeners.; North Carolina Cooperative Extension-Master Gardeners (Folder 2:5.22)